Guide to the Paul Jeffrey Papers, 1969-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Paul Jeffrey papers 1969-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jeffrey, Paul, 1933-
145 linear feet Extent: Approximately 3500 Items
Paul H. Jeffrey is a saxophonist, composer, arranger, and educator, professionally active in music since the 1950s. The Paul Jeffrey Papers have as their focal point nearly 1,400 manuscript scores and parts that Jeffrey composed or arranged for big band jazz ensemble, primarily for the Duke Jazz Ensemble. Also present are audio and moving image materials, photographs and posters, as well as correspondence, promotional materials, and written records relating to various aspects of Jeffrey's career.
RL.00634
Language: Material in English and Italian
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, all original audio and moving image materials are CLOSED to patron listening and/or viewing. However, researchers can access the original artifacts for the purpose of reading liner notes and carrying out other text-based studies. CD or DVD use copies, which are OPEN to patron use, are available for some items and are noted below. Unless otherwise noted, use copies must be made for access to audio and moving image content.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Paul Jeffrey Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2007, 2009, and 2010.
Biographical Note
Paul H. Jeffrey (b. April 8, 1933) is a saxophonist, composer, arranger, and educator. After completing a Bachelor's Degree in Music Education from Ithaca College in 1955, Jeffrey went on to pursue a successful professional music career. In the late 1950s and early 1960s, Jeffrey toured the U.S. with blues and jazz musicians including Wynonie Harris, B.B. King, Illinois Jacquet, and Elmo Hope. He then spent much of the 1960s working with Dizzy Gillespie, Clark Terry, the Count Basie Orchestra, and others, while also releasing several recordings as a leader beginning in 1968. Jeffrey enjoyed lasting associations with both Thelonious Monk and Charles Mingus for much of the 1970s, working as a saxophonist and arranger for many of their recordings during that time.
Beginning in the 1970s, Jeffrey also enjoyed a prolific career in education, serving on the music faculties at the University of Hartford, Rutgers University, Jersey City State College, and others. In 1983, he joined the Duke University music faculty as Artist in Residence and Director of Jazz Studies, a position he held until his retirement in 2003. Jeffrey is currently Professor of the Practice Emeritus in Duke University's Department of Music.
Collection Overview
The Paul Jeffrey Papers span the dates 1969 to 2006. The papers have as their focal point nearly 1,400 manuscript scores and parts that Jeffrey composed or arranged for big band jazz ensemble, primarily for the Duke Jazz Ensemble. The papers also include photographs, posters, and other written records of Jeffrey's musical career since the 1960s. There are additionally over 500 hours of concert and studio recordings in a number of audio and moving image formats that date since the 1960s. These formats include audiocassettes, open reel audio tapes, compact discs, digital audio tapes, long-playing records, VHS, and Hi-8 video cassettes. The collection is arranged into the following five series: Correspondence, Promotional Material, and Festival Records; Photographs and Posters; Audio and Moving Image Materials; Music Manuscripts; and Oversize Music Manuscripts. Audio and Moving Image Materials are arranged by format, and Music Manuscripts are arranged alphabetically. Acquired as a part of the Jazz Archive at Duke University.
Subject Headings
Audiocassettes; Big band music -- Scores and parts; Compact discs; Composers -- United States; Digital audio tapes; Duke University. Dept of Music -- Faculty; Hi-8.; Jeffrey, Paul, 1933-; Jazz; Jazz musicians; Long-playing records; Music -- Instruction and study; Photographs; Posters; Saxophonists -- United States; VHS
Detailed Description of Collection
- Series I: Correspondence, Promotional Material, and Festival Records, 1969-2006, (3 boxes)
  Written materials related primarily to Jeffrey's tenure as Director of Jazz Studies at Duke University, though also including material detailing Jeffrey's performing career prior to Duke. See Box 4 for related posters.
  - Duke University Faculty Records, 1983-2006 (2 folders) (Box 1)
    Chiefly correspondence between Jeffrey and various Duke administrators regarding Jeffrey's teaching and jazz programming.
  - Duke University Jazz Concerts, 1984-2001 (7 folders) (Box 1)
    Clippings, rehearsal schedules, brochures, correspondence, advertisements, press kits, and contracts relating to visiting jazz artists for the annual concert series of the Duke Jazz Ensemble.
  - Paul Jeffrey Performances and Programs, 1969-2001 (6 folders) (Box 1)
    Clippings, correspondence, and advertisements related to Jeffrey's studio recordings and various performances from the 1970s through the 1990s, including directing the jazz ensembles at the Aspen Music Ensemble, the McDonald's All-American High School Band, and touring with the Newark Boys School.
  - Mary Lou Williams Jazz Festival, 1983-1991 (1 folder) (Box 1)
    Clippings, correspondence, and advertisements related to the festival.
  - Thomas Chapin and John Coltrane Material, 1986-1998 (2 folders) (Box 1)
    Miscellaneous clippings and correspondence related to the lives and careers of Coltrane and Chapin. See also labeled video cassettes in Box 13 for Chapin memorial.
  - North Carolina Umbria Jazz Festival/International Jazz Festival, 1969-2001, bulk post-1983 (12 folders) (Box 2)
    Programs, instrument clinic syllabi, contracts, receipts, press releases, scrapbooks, and photographs related to the festival.
    - Clippings, 1969-1997 (5 folders) (Box 2)
    - Concert Programs, 1983-2001 (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - Business Records, 1984-2000 (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - Thelonious Monk Jazz Institute, 1982-1991 (5 folders) (Box 3)
    Programs, clippings, correspondence, institute proposal, and Monk obituary.
- Series II: Photographs and Posters, 1983-2006, (2 boxes)
  Photographic prints and oversize posters, most of which are related to files in Series I. Of note are the photos of Jeffrey with Thelonious Monk in Box 3, including one signed by Monk, and other signed publicity photos by Jimmy Heath, Lionel Hampton, Christian McBride, Art Blakey, Sonny Rollins, and others.
  - Jeffrey Performance and Publicity Shots (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Musician Publicity Shots (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Candid Shots with Jeffrey (1 folder) (Box 3)
  - Slides (1 folder) (Box 3)
  - Concert Posters (4 folders, oversize) (Box 4)
- Series III: Audio and Moving Image Materials, 1969-2003 and undated, (34 boxes)
  Contains audio and moving image materials in a variety of formats, including open reel audio tapes, audiocassettes, LPs, compact discs, digital audio tapes, VHS videocassettes, and Hi8. Materials are chiefly related to Jeffrey's time as director of the jazz programs at Rutgers and at Duke, including recordings of the Duke Jazz Ensemble, of visiting jazz musicians, and of various performances by Paul Jeffrey. Jeffrey's associations with the Aspen Music Festival and the North Carolina Umbria Jazz Festival are also documented. Additionally, the series contains commercial audio recordings (CDs and LPs) featuring Paul Jeffrey as a sideman or as a leader.
  Arranged by format (audio cassettes, long-playing records, etc), and further subdivided into subject groupings. Original titles are retained.
  RESTRICTED: All original audio and moving image materials (Boxes 5-37, 207) are CLOSED to patron use. However, researchers can access the original artifacts for the purpose of reading liner notes and carrying out other text-based studies. CD or DVD use copies, which are OPEN to patron use, are available for some items and are noted below. Unless otherwise noted, use copies must be made for access to content.
  - Audio Cassettes, 1982-2000 and undated
    - Aspen Music Festival (July 31, 1993 - July 27, 1996 and undated) (13 cassettes) (Box 5)
    - Duke Jazz Ensemble Concerts (April 17, 1988 - October 27, 2000) (8 cassettes) (Box 5)
    - Other, undated (15 cassettes) (Box 5)
      Chiefly master classes and concerts from Jeffrey's time at Hartford, Rutgers, and Duke. Includes recordings of concerts by Paul Jeffrey, Chevy Chase, Sonny Stitt, Lionel Hampton, Wynton Marsalis, and Sam Rivers.
    - Unlabeled (53 cassettes) (Box 6)
  - Compact Discs, 1992, 1997, and undated
    - Curtis Fuller / Paul Jeffrey Sextet, Together in Monaco (1997). (Box 7)
    - Paul Jeffrey, Live in Caorle, Italy (undated). (Box 7)
    - Paul Jeffrey, 'Round Midnight in North Carolina and Dolo (1991). (Box 7)
  - Digital Audio Tapes, March 1992-August 1999 and undated
    Chiefly recordings of Duke Jazz Ensemble concerts in 1998-1999. Some tapes unlabeled and undated.
    - Audio Tapes (29 tapes) (Box 7)
  - Long-Playing Records, 1972-1988 and undated, (16 records)
    - Cecil Payne, Zodiac (undated) (Box 8)
    - Charles Mingus, Cumbia, and Jazz Fusion (1978) (Box 8)
    - Charles Mingus, His Final Work (1977) (Box 8)
    - Charles Mingus, His Last Recording Sessions (1980) (Box 8)
    - Charles Mingus, Me, Myself, an Eye (1979) (Box 8)
    - Charles Mingus, Three or Four Shades of Blues (1977) (Box 8)
    - Duke's 50 Year Tradition of Big Bands (undated) (Box 8)
    - Giovanni Tommaso Quintet, Via G.T. (1986) (Box 8)
    - Lionel Hampton and His Big Band, Made in Japan (rec. 1983) (Box 8)
    - Paul Jeffrey, Electrifying Sounds of the Paul Jeffrey Quintet (undated) (Box 8)
    - Paul Jeffrey, Family (1972) [no LP; cover only] (Box 8)
    - Paul Jeffrey, Paul Jeffrey (1974) (Box 8)
    - Paul Jeffrey, Watershed (1972) (Box 8)
    - Perugia Big Band, Jazz in Umbria (1982) (Box 8)
    - Soul Makossa, Afrique (undated) (Box 8)
    - Umbria Jazz All-Stars, Rita Marcotulli / Pietro Tonolo Quartet (1988) (Box 8)
  - VHS Video Cassettes, 1981-1999
    - Duke Jazz Ensemble, February 24, 1981-November 17, 1995 and undated (Box 9)
    - Duke Jazz Ensemble and Duke campus jazz events, February 28, 1992-February 28, 1997 and undated (Box 10)
      Includes "Reflections on the Monk Institute"
    - North Carolina Umbria Jazz Festival, 1987-1996 and undated (Box 11)
    - North Carolina Umbria Jazz Festival, and various concerts, 1988-1997 and undated) (Box 12)
      Includes the Thomas Chapin memorial concert.
    - Jeffrey Performances, guest artists in Raleigh/Durham, April 24, 1988-August 13, 1999 and undated (Box 13)
      Includes concerts by Lou Donaldson, Frank Morgan, Bud Shank, Buddy Rich, Alvin Baptiste, and Cassandra Wilson.
    - Various Concerts, undated (Box 14)
      Includes concerts by Curtis Fuller, McCoy Tyner, Ralph Peterson, Paul Jeffrey, and the Italian All-Stars.
    - Various Concerts, undated (Box 15)
      Includes concerts by John Hicks, Gary Bartz, Sonny Rollins, Michael Sloter, Frank Morgan, and Marie Sharp.
    - Unlabeled (15 cassettes) (Box 16)
    - Unlabeled (15 cassettes) (Box 17)
    - Unlabeled (16 cassettes) (Box 18)
    - Unlabeled (15 cassettes) (Box 19)
  - Hi8 Video Cassettes, 1996-2003
    Recordings of Paul Jeffrey concerts and Duke Jazz Ensemble concerts.
    - Duke Jazz Ensemble Concerts, 1996-2003 (Box 20)
      Includes concerts with guest musicians Ralph Peterson, Antoine Roney, Curtis Fuller, Walter Bishop, and Barry Harris.
    - Jeffrey Concerts in Italy, 1998-1999 (Box 21)
    - Jeffrey Concerts in Italy and at the Aspen Music Festival, 1996-1999 (Box 22)
    - Unlabeled (31 cassettes) (Box 23)
  - Open Reel Audio Tapes, 1969-1984 and undated, (169 reels)
    Quarter-inch tape, on 5, 7, and 10 1/2 inch reels. Chiefly containing Rutgers Livingston Jazz Ensemble Concerts from 1980 and 1981, with some reels unlabeled or labeled "rehearsal," "practice," or "octet."
    - Open reel tapes (Box 24)
    - Open reel tapes (Box 25)
    - Open reel tapes (Box 26)
    - Open reel tapes (Box 28)
    - Open reel tapes (Box 29)
    - Open reel tapes (Box 30)
    - Open reel tapes (Box 31)
    - Open reel tapes (Box 32)
    - Open reel tapes (Box 33)
    - Open reel tapes (Box 34)
    - Open reel tapes (Box 35)
    - Open reel tapes (Box 36)
    - Open reel tapes (Box 37)
    - Open reel tapes (Box 207)
  - Other Formats, 1973-1987
    - Beta, 6 cassettes, 1985-1987 and undated (Box 27)
      Includes concerts by the Duke Jazz Ensemble, Paul Jeffrey, and Herbie Hancock at the North Carolina Umbria Jazz Festival.
    - Helical Scan Video, 2 reels, 1973 (Box 27)
      Concert by Paul Jeffrey.
    - U-matic, 4 cassettes, 1984 and undated (Box 27)
      Concerts by the Duke Jazz Ensemble and Terri Lyne Carrington at Duke.
- Series IV: Music Manuscripts, 1983-2003 and undated, (103 boxes)
  Approximately 800 compositions for jazz ensemble, including both published and unpublished materials. This series contains a substantial collection of Jeffrey's compositions and arrangements for the Duke University Jazz Ensemble, including works written for both standard big band instrumentation as well as non-standard instrumentations. It additionally contains commercially published compositions and other miscellaneous manuscripts.
  The series consists chiefly of instrumental parts organized by composition title, with different versions and copies of the same composition grouped together. Most of the materials are undated. Includes hand-written manuscripts, photocopies, and manuscripts produced on a laser printer. Many are unbound; please handle carefully and keep pages in their original order.
  Series also includes six boxes of miscellaneous instrumental parts organized alphabetically by title, placed at the end of the series.
  - 1st Georgia Soli 'On Cue (Box 38)
  - 1st Night Blues (Box 38)
  - 40s Swing Medley (Box 38)
  - 502 Blues, (2 folders) (Box 38)
  - 59th Street Bridge Song, The (Box 38)
  - Acousia (Box 38)
  - Advance Notice, (2 folders) (Box 38)
  - African Aztec, (2 folders) (Box 38)
  - African Sunrise (Box 38)
  - After After Hours (Box 38)
  - After the Morning, (2 folders) (Box 38)
  - Again Again, (2 folders) (Box 39)
  - Ah, So (Box 39)
  - Air Jordan (Box 39)
  - Air Mail Special, (3 folders) (Box 39)
  - Airegin, (3 folders) (Box 39)
  - Air-Mail (Box 39)
  - Ala Mode, (4 folders) (Box 39)
  - Alice in Wonderland, (2 folders) (Box 40)
  - All My Life (Box 40)
  - All of Me (Box 40)
  - All the Things You Are, (2 folders) (Box 40)
  - Alterations, (3 folders) (Box 40)
  - Amanda's Song, (3 folders) (Box 40)
  - Amazing Grace (Box 40)
  - American Patrol (Box 40)
  - Angelica, (5 folders) (Box 41)
  - Animal Instincts, (6 folders) (Box 41)
  - Another Shade Of The Blues (Box 41)
  - Apple Honey (Box 41)
  - Apple Turnover, (7 folders) (Box 42)
  - Arabia, (2 folders) (Box 42)
  - Armageddon (Box 42)
  - Art of War, The (Box 42)
  - Arthur's Theme (Box 42)
  - Assessment, (2 folders) (Box 42)
  - Atholete, The, (3 folders) (Box 43)
  - Attainment, (3 folders) (Box 43)
  - Au Privave (Box 43)
  - Autumn in New York, (2 folders) (Box 43)
  - Bach to Bach (Box 43)
  - Back in the Days, (4 folders) (Box 43)
  - Barbara Ann (Box 44)
  - Basie (Box 44)
  - Be Bop, (3 folders) (Box 44)
  - Be Bop Irishman, (3 folders) (Box 44)
  - Be Bop Minor (Box 44)
  - Be Nice to Me (Box 44)
  - Bean and the Boys, (2 folders) (Box 44)
  - Beatrice, (2 folders) (Box 44)
  - Beatrice (Box 45)
  - Beauteous (Box 45)
  - Beethoven Meets the Millenium in Spain, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - Before You (Box 45)
  - Believers, The (Box 45)
  - Bella Carolina, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - Bemsha Swing, (4 folders) (Box 45)
  - Ben (Box 46)
  - Benji's Bounce (Box 46)
  - Bernie's Tune, (3 folders) (Box 46)
  - Bert's Blues (Box 46)
  - Better All the Time (Box 46)
  - Better Git It in Your Soul (Box 46)
  - Between the Devil and the Deep Blue Sea (Box 46)
  - Beware of Dreams, (2 folders) (Box 46)
  - Beyond the Blue, (3 folders) (Box 46)
  - Big Bad Blues (Box 47)
  - Big Beat, The, (5 folders) (Box 47)
  - Big Jim Blues (Box 47)
  - Big P, (3 folders) (Box 47)
  - Bigfoot (Box 47)
  - Bird, The, (3 folders) (Box 48)
  - Blue Daniel, (2 folders) (Box 48)
  - Blue Devil, The (Box 48)
  - Blue Monk, (2 folders) (Box 48)
  - Blue Moon (Box 48)
  - Blue Skies (Box 48)
  - Blue Spring (Box 48)
  - Blues ala Burgess, (3 folders) (Box 49)
  - Blues Behavior, (2 folders) (Box 49)
  - Blues for Brown, (2 folders) (Box 49)
  - Blues for Corinne (Box 49)
  - Blues for Ivan Symonds, A (Box 49)
  - Blues for Sale (Box 49)
  - Blues in the Pocket (Box 49)
  - Blues March (Box 49)
  - Blues Medley (Box 50)
  - Body and Soul, (7 folders) (Box 50)
  - Bold Steps, (3 folders) (Box 50)
  - Bolivia (Box 50)
  - Bondage, (2 folders) (Box 51)
  - Boogie Stop Shuffle (Box 51)
  - Bossa Medley (Box 51)
  - Bouncin' with Bud, (2 folders) (Box 51)
  - Braithawaite, (2 folders) (Box 51)
  - Braith-A-Way (Box 51)
  - Brand New World (Box 51)
  - Brand X (Box 51)
  - Brasilia (Box 51)
  - Brazil (Box 52)
  - Bright Mississippi, (2 folders) (Box 52)
  - Brookland (Box 52)
  - Brooklyn Nights (Box 52)
  - Brownie Speaks, (3 folders) (Box 52)
  - Brush Taps (Box 52)
  - Bud's Blues, (4 folders) (Box 52)
  - Bu's Delight, (9 folders) (Box 53)
  - Bu's Delight, (3 folders) (Box 54)
  - But Not For Me (Box 54)
  - Bye Ya, (2 folders) (Box 54)
  - C Jam Blues (Box 54)
  - C T A (Box 54)
  - C.P. Time (Box 54)
  - Cabu (Box 54)
  - Candu (Box 54)
  - Cape Verdean (Box 54)
  - Cape Verdean, (2 folders) (Box 55)
  - Captain Blued (Box 55)
  - Caravan, (4 folders) (Box 55)
  - Carolina Moon (Box 55)
  - Celia, (3 folders) (Box 55)
  - Century Rag, (3 folders) (Box 56)
  - Chaniece, (3 folders) (Box 56)
  - Chattanooga Choo Choo (Box 56)
  - Chedlike, (2 folders) (Box 56)
  - Chelsea Bridge (Box 56)
  - Cherokee (Box 56)
  - Cherry Juice (Box 56)
  - Chess Players, The (Box 56)
  - Chicago (Box 56)
  - Chi-Chi (Box 57)
  - Children of Sanchez (Box 57)
  - Chips (Box 57)
  - Christopher Columbus (Box 57)
  - Clarion (Box 57)
  - Clean Sweep (Box 57)
  - Close Enough for Love (Box 57)
  - Closest to the Sun, (2 folders) (Box 57)
  - Coffee Pot, (5 folders) (Box 57)
  - Come Gone, (2 folders) (Box 58)
  - Come Rain or Come Shine (Box 58)
  - Come Rain or Shine (Box 58)
  - Come Sunday (Box 58)
  - Coming on the Hudson, (3 folders) (Box 58)
  - Confab in Tempo, (3 folders) (Box 58)
  - Congeniality (Box 58)
  - Construct (Box 58)
  - Cool Blues (Box 59)
  - Coral Keys (Box 59)
  - Coral Reef (Box 59)
  - Cottonmouth (Box 59)
  - Cottontail, (3 folders) (Box 59)
  - Countdown (Box 59)
  - Countin' the Blues (Box 59)
  - Crackdown (Box 59)
  - Cram 'n Exam, (2 folders) (Box 59)
  - Crazy Rhythm (Box 59)
  - Crepuscule with Nellie, (2 folders) (Box 60)
  - Cry for Understanding, A, (6 folders) (Box 60)
  - Cry of Hunger (Box 60)
  - Cubano Chant, (2 folders) (Box 60)
  - Cubicle (Box 61)
  - Cute (Box 61)
  - D Concert (Box 61)
  - Daily Affirmation, (3 folders) (Box 61)
  - Dance of the Infidels, (5 folders) (Box 61)
  - Dancing on the Ceiling (Box 61)
  - Darben the Redd Foxx (Box 62)
  - Dark and Lovely (Box 62)
  - Darn that Dream (Box 62)
  - Dauphin Dance (Box 62)
  - Days of Wine and Roses (Box 62)
  - Dear John, (2 folders) (Box 62)
  - Deep Basie Blues (Box 62)
  - Deux Battements de Coeur (Box 62)
  - Devil Woman (Box 62)
  - Dewey Square (Box 62)
  - Dig, (2 folders) (Box 62)
  - Dixie Medley (Box 62)
  - Do I Do (Box 62)
  - Doc's Holiday (Box 62)
  - Donna Lee, (2 folders) (Box 63)
  - Don't Git Sassy (Box 63)
  - Don't Take Your Love (Box 63)
  - Don't You Worry 'Bout a Thing (Box 63)
  - Doodlin' (Box 63)
  - Down Basie Street (Box 63)
  - Down for the Count (Box 63)
  - Doxy, (2 folders) (Box 63)
  - Dream Little Boy Dream, (2 folders) (Box 63)
  - Dreamsville (Box 63)
  - Drum Roll (Box 63)
  - Drum Squad, The (Box 63)
  - Drum Suite (Box 63)
  - DX (Box 63)
  - Early Autumn (Box 63)
  - Ease On Down the Road (Box 63)
  - Easy Time, (2 folders) (Box 64)
  - Ebony Moonbeams (Box 64)
  - Ecclusiastics (Box 64)
  - Egg Hunt, (6 folders) (Box 64)
  - Egyptian Dune Dance (Box 64)
  - Einstein (Box 64)
  - Elda (Box 65)
  - Elija, (3 folders) (Box 65)
  - Ellington Medley, (2 folders) (Box 65)
  - Ellingtonia (Box 65)
  - Elsa (Box 65)
  - Emancipation Blues (Box 65)
  - Emily, (2 folders) (Box 65)
  - Epistrophy, (4 folders) (Box 66)
  - Epistrophy, (4 folders) (Box 66)
  - Eronel, (4 folders) (Box 66)
  - Eronel Score, (2 folders) (Box 66)
  - Estevanico's Journey (Box 67)
  - Eternal Triangle, The, (3 folders) (Box 67)
  - Evergreen (Box 67)
  - Every Corner (Box 67)
  - Everyday I Get the Blues (Box 67)
  - Evidence, (4 folders) (Box 67)
  - Exhilaration, (2 folders) (Box 67)
  - Exit Swinging (Box 68)
  - Extrasensory Perception (Box 68)
  - Eye of the Hurricane (Box 68)
  - Eye of the Tiger (Box 68)
  - Fallout (Box 68)
  - Fancy Free (Box 68)
  - Fanfares and Tags (Box 68)
  - Fantail (Box 68)
  - Farmer's Market, (2 folders) (Box 68)
  - Feed the People (Box 68)
  - Feel Like Making Love (Box 68)
  - Feelin' No Evil (Box 68)
  - Fingers (Box 68)
  - Fire Fly (Box 68)
  - First Night Blues (Box 68)
  - Float Like a Butterfly, Sting Like a Bee (Box 68)
  - Foggy Day, A (Box 69)
  - Folklore, (3 folders) (Box 69)
  - Folks Meet Our Drummer, (3 folders) (Box 69)
  - Footprints (Box 69)
  - For Elmo, Sonny, and Freddie, (3 folders) (Box 69)
  - For Once In My Life (Box 69)
  - For the Elders (Box 69)
  - For Uncle Harvey, (2 folders) (Box 69)
  - Forever Sonny (Box 69)
  - Four Brothers, (2 folders) (Box 69)
  - Four In One (Box 69)
  - Four On the Outside, (2 folders) (Box 69)
  - Freedom Jazz Dance (Box 70)
  - Freedom Shout (Box 70)
  - Friday the 13th (Box 70)
  - Friday The Thirteenth (Box 70)
  - Fried Bananas (Box 70)
  - Friend (Box 70)
  - Friend or Foe (Box 70)
  - Front Burner (Box 70)
  - Fruit, The (Box 70)
  - Fulton Street Theme, (4 folders) (Box 70)
  - Fum, (2 folders) (Box 70)
  - Fun Time (Box 70)
  - Funny Blues (Box 70)
  - Gabrielle's Balloon, (3 folders) (Box 71)
  - Getaway (Box 71)
  - Ghost Butter (Box 71)
  - Giant Steps, (2 folders) (Box 71)
  - Giddybug Gallop (Box 71)
  - Ginger Flower Song, (2 folders) (Box 71)
  - Girl From Ipanema, The, (2 folders) (Box 71)
  - Girl Talk (Box 71)
  - Glass Enclosure (Box 71)
  - Glory of Love, The (Box 71)
  - God Bless the Child (Box 71)
  - Gone, (7 folders) (Box 72)
  - Gonna Fly Now - Rocky (Box 72)
  - Good Bait, (3 folders) (Box 72)
  - Good Life, The, (3 folders) (Box 72)
  - Goodbye Pork Pie Hat (Box 72)
  - Gotsta' Be a Better Way (Box 73)
  - Green Dolphin (Box 73)
  - Gringo (Box 73)
  - Groove Blues (Box 73)
  - Groovin' (Box 73)
  - Growing Pains, (2 folders) (Box 73)
  - H.C. Show (Box 73)
  - Haitian Fight Song (Box 73)
  - Hallelujah, (2 folders) (Box 73)
  - Hallucinations, (3 folders) (Box 73)
  - Hamlet's Favorite Son, (2 folders) (Box 74)
  - Hamp (Box 74)
  - Hamp's Boogie, (3 folders) (Box 74)
  - Hamp's Got the Blues (Box 74)
  - Hamp's The Champ (Box 74)
  - Hang in There (Box 74)
  - Hank's Other Bag, (3 folders) (Box 74)
  - Happy (Box 74)
  - Harlem Air Shaft (Box 75)
  - Harlequin Tears (Box 75)
  - Hassles (Box 75)
  - Hava Nice Day (Box 75)
  - Heat's On, The (Box 75)
  - Heaviness of Blue, The (Box 75)
  - Helen's Song, (5 folders) (Box 75)